Linda A. Towle and Marjorie Howard Towle Papers and Tufts Memorabilia MS266
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Linda A. Towle and Marjorie Howard Towle Papers and Tufts Memorabilia
1916 -- 2019
circa 1931 -- 1935, 1965 -- 1969
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
MS266
1.88 Linear Feet 1 record box, 1 half size record box, and 2 flat files
27.9 Megabytes
124 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Linda A. Towle, 2019, accession MS-2019-089, and 2020, accessions MS-2021-006 and MS-2021-008.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series: Marjorie Howard Towle materials and Linda A. Towle materials.
Biographical / Historical
Marjorie Rose Howard Towle (March 2, 1913 – January 11, 1989) attended Jackson College for Women from 1931-1933, and her daughter, Linda A. Towle (September 24, 1947 – ) graduated from Jackson College in 1969.
Marjorie Howard was born in Burlington, Vermont to Enos and Emma Barney Howard. After studying English at Jackson College from 1931-1933, she transferred to the University of Vermont. She completed her English degree at the University of Vermont, where she participated in the Dramatic Club and graduated as a member of the Class of 1935. Before marrying, Marjorie Towle worked as a clerk. She married Charles Towle on March 8, 1942, gave birth to her daughter Linda in 1947, and then worked as a homemaker. Marjorie Howard Towle died in Burlington, Vermont on January 11, 1989.
Linda A. Towle was born to Marjorie and Charles Towle on September 24, 1947. She entered Jackson College for Women in 1965 where she studied economics. Linda A. Towle was president of her sorority, Alpha Omicron Pi, during her senior year, though she helped close the chapter prior to the end of the 1968-1969 academic year. She later received a Master's degree in prehistoric archaeology and went on to work as an archaeologist in Massachusetts and Colorado. She was a Supervisory Archeologist for the Eastern Archeological Field Laboratory of the National Park Service, an archaeological consultant for the Massachusetts Audubon Society, chief archaeologist at Mesa Verde National Park in Colorado, and board president of the Cortez Historical Society in Cortez, Colorado.
Other Finding Aids
A printed copy of an item-level inventory created by the donor is in box 1. The inventory does not directly correspond to the physical arrangement of the material in the collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the papers of Marjorie Howard Towle and Linda A. Towle, including calendars, clippings, correspondence, event programs, photographs, sorority materials, and Tufts memorabilia and publications. The material dates from 1931-1935 and 1965-1969.
Marjorie Howard Towle's material relates to her two years as a student at Jackson College from 1931-1933 and includes scanned photographs dating from her early childhood through the end of her life. Sorority materials include invitations to join various sororities and a newspaper announcement reporting her decision to pledge to Sigma Kappa. Photographs of Marjorie Howard Towle and other Jackson College students date from 1931 to 1933. Additional Tufts memorabilia includes sheet music, programs from and clippings about plays in which Towle acted, dance programs, and Tufts publications.
Linda A. Towle's material is also related to her time as a student at Jackson College from 1965-1969. Correspondence includes letters from Tufts regarding tuition, rooming, and insurance; invitations to social events; and cards from classmates. Sorority materials from Linda A. Towle's time as a member of Alpha Omicron Pi include her certificate of initiation, correspondence, hazing materials, invitations, and printed and scanned photographs. Newspaper clippings relate to Jackson College. Other material documenting Towle's time as a Jackson College student include dormitory sign-out cards, personal calendars, lists of personal expenses, and photographs. Additional Tufts memorabilia includes event programs, a Jackson College Class of 1969 beanie, and Tufts publications. Born-digital material provided by the donor includes scans of photographs, spreadsheets with detailed calendars for each academic year, and narratives about Marjorie Howard Towle's and her own experiences at Jackson College.
Tufts University -- History; Student life
- Marjorie Howard Towle materials, 1916 -- 1935; 1931 -- 1935; MS266.000001; 30 Digital Object(s); 13.3 Megabytes
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents Marjorie Howard Towle's time as a student at Jackson College from 1931 -- 1933 and also includes scanned photographs that date from her early childhood through the end of her life. Records include clippings, correspondence, dance programs, photographs, playbills, sorority materials, and Tufts publications.
  - Dance programs, sorority materials, playbills, and clippings, 1931 -- 1935; MS266.000020 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open for research.
  - Photographs, 1916 -- 1988; MS266.000130; 13.3 Megabytes; 30 Digital Object(s); 1 Folder(s)
    - Marjorie Howard at age 3, 1916; MS266.000131; 762.8 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie Howard on horseback, 1923; MS266.000132; 1.4 Megabytes
    - Marjorie Howard, left, as Red Cross volunteer, 1930; MS266.000133; 432.9 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie Howard on the set of Green Stockings, 1931; MS266.000134; 1.2 Megabytes
    - Marjorie Howard high school graduation portrait, 1931; MS266.000135; 1.5 Megabytes
    - Photographs, 1931 -- 1933; MS266.000021 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Marjorie Howard on high school graduation day, 1931 June 19; MS266.000136; 90.8 Kilobytes
    - Formal portrait of Marjorie Howard, 1931; MS266.000137; 434.1 Kilobytes
    - Ean and Emma Howard posed next to car, 1931; MS266.000138; 488.4 Kilobytes
    - Zoe Bodman and Marjorie Howard in bathing costumes, 1931; MS266.000139; 422.5 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie with father Ean Howard posed in front of house at 275 South Winooski Avenue, Burlington, Vermont, 1932 January 03; MS266.000140; 99.1 Kilobytes
    - Formal portrait of Marjorie Howard, 1935; MS266.000141; 972.6 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie Howard on horseback, 1941; MS266.000142; 793 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie Howard and Charlie Towle's wedding, 1942 March 08; MS266.000143; 1 Megabytes
    - Marjorie Towle and Charlie Towle in uniform posed in front of car, 1942; MS266.000144; 94.6 Kilobytes
    - Formal portrait of Marjorie Howard, 1943; MS266.000145; 86.2 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie Towle cross-country skiing, circa 1946 -- 1947; MS266.000146; 126.3 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie and Linda Towle in front of Christmas tree, 1947; MS266.000147; 25.3 Kilobytes
    - Emma Howard, Rose Barney, and Linda and Marjorie Towle, 1948; MS266.000148; 356.5 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie and Linda Towle, 1949; MS266.000149; 80.1 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie, Linda, and Charlie Towle posed in front of car, 1954; MS266.000150; 153.7 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie and Linda Towle on Easter Sunday, 1955; MS266.000151; 136.4 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie and Linda Towle on Easter Sunday, 1960; MS266.000152; 123.8 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie Towle with dog, 1960; MS266.000153; 264.4 Kilobytes
    - Babs Keene (left) and other women at Jackson College 30th reunion, 1965; MS266.000154; 512.9 Kilobytes
    - Babs Keene and Marjorie Towle, 1969; MS266.000155; 157.1 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie Towle posed in front of car with Charlie Towle's skis, 1971; MS266.000156; 19.8 Kilobytes
    - Linda, Marjorie, and Charlie Towle at retirement party, 1975; MS266.000157; 585.8 Kilobytes
    - Charlie and Marjorie Towle's 40th anniversary, 1982; MS266.000158; 208.2 Kilobytes
    - Linda, Marjorie, and Charlie Towle, 1982; MS266.000159; 342.9 Kilobytes
    - Marjorie and Charlie Towle's 47th anniversary, 1988; MS266.000160; 211 Kilobytes
  - Correspondence, clippings, and Tufts publications, 1931 -- 1933; MS266.000022 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Freshmen Commandments poster, 1934 -- 1935; MS266.000023 (Box Shared 126)
- Linda A. Towle materials, 1965 -- 1969, 2011, 2019; 1965 -- 1969; MS266.000002; 94 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains material that documents Linda A. Towle's time as a student at Jackson College from 1965 -- 1969. Records include clippings, correspondence, photographs, Alpha Omicron Pi sorority materials, tuition bills and personal expenses, and Tufts publications. Scanned photographs in this series were provided by the donor. Calendar spreadsheets were compiled by the donor by consulting the paper calendars in this series as well as letters.
  - Correspondence, clippings, and Tufts publications, 1965 -- 1968; MS266.000025 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hazing materials, 1965 September; MS266.000026 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personal calendars, 1965 -- 1969; MS266.000027 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Freshman Calendar, 2019; MS266.000028
  - Sophomore Calendar, 2019; MS266.000029
  - Junior Calendar, 2019; MS266.000030
  - Senior Calendar, 2019; MS266.000031
  - Photographs, 1965 -- 1969; MS266.000032 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    The photographs in this file were scanned and transferred to DCA by the donor. Individuals, dates, and locations were also identified by the donor.
    - Metcalf Christmas Tree, 1965; MS266.000033 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Vi Bekeris playing guitar, 1965; MS266.000034 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sue Relyea playing guitar, 1965; MS266.000035 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle in dorm, 1965; MS266.000036 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle, Sue Relyea, Vi Bekeris, and Chris Ruffer, 1965; MS266.000037 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cheryl Brown, Sylvia Soffron, Sue Relyea, and Vi Bekeris, 1965; MS266.000038 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle's 18th birthday, 1965 September 24; MS266.000039 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle's 18th birthday, 1965 September 24; MS266.000040 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Birthday cards on display in dorm, 1965; MS266.000041 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dorm room, 1965; MS266.000042 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Metcalf and West dorms, 1965; MS266.000043 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Creating bunk beds in Metcalf, 1966; MS266.000044 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bunk beds in Metcalf, 1966; MS266.000045 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Snow behind Metcalf, 1966; MS266.000046 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Snow on hill, Goddard Chapel, 1966; MS266.000047 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dorm door decorated for Linda Towle pledging to Alpha Omicron Pi, 1966; MS266.000048 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle pledges Alpha Omicron Pi, 1966; MS266.000049 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Vi Bekeris and friend from home, 1966 March 12; MS266.000050 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda A. Towle's Alpha Omicron Pi initiation certificate, 1966 April 25; MS266.000051 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle and Tom Poulin dressed for Alpha Omicron Pi Pledge Formal, 1966 April 16; MS266.000052 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Group of women posed with Alpha Omicron Pi Initiation dog paddles and stuffed animals, 1966 April 25; MS266.000053 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Group of women posed with Alpha Omicron Pi Initiation dog paddles and stuffed animals, 1966 April 25; MS266.000054 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda A. Towle portrait, 1966; MS266.000055 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chris Ruffer, Vi Bekeris, and Sue Relyea in bed in dorm, 1966; MS266.000056 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Vi Bekeris, Linda Towle, Patience Sampson, and Chris Ruffer in bed in dorm, 1966; MS266.000057 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Vi Bekeris and Sue Relyea in bunk beds in dorm, 1966; MS266.000058 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chris Ruffer and Sue Relyea in dorm, 1966; MS266.000059 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Patience Sampson in bed in dorm, 1966; MS266.000060 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chris Ruffer and other students moving bed in dorm, 1966; MS266.000061 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Black cat perched on windowsill in dorm, 1966; MS266.000062 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - View of building and trees on Tufts campus, 1966; MS266.000063 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle, age 19, cutting birthday cake with friends, 1966 September 24; MS266.000064 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle eating birthday cake next to gifts in dorm, 1966 September 24; MS266.000065 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bush Hall dorm room, Linda Towle and Vi Bekeris, 1966; MS266.000066 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bush Hall dorm room, 1966; MS266.000067 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bush Hall dorm room, 1966; MS266.000068 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bush Hall dorm room, 1966; MS266.000069 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle dressed in costume for Alpha Omicron Pi event, 1966 October 29; MS266.000070 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Men and women at Sunday open house in dorm room, 1966 November 13; MS266.000071 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle in dress and gloves in dorm room, 1966 November 19; MS266.000072 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Flowers in a vase in dorm room, 1966; MS266.000073 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Susan Perlmutter's (Jackson 1968) birthday in dorm room, 1967; MS266.000074 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Susan Perlmutter's birthday in dorm room, with Molly Houston (Jackson 1969) on left, 1967; MS266.000075 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle Alpha Omicron Pi sorority portrait, 1967; MS266.000076 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omicron Pi skit, 1967 February 9; MS266.000077 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omicron Pi skit, 1967 February 9; MS266.000078 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omicron Pi skit, 1967 February 9; MS266.000079 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omicron Pi skit, 1967 February 9; MS266.000080 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omicron Pi skit, 1967 February 9; MS266.000081 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omicron Pi new pledge class, 1967 April 10; MS266.000082 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omicron Pi new pledge class, 1967 April 10; MS266.000083 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Debbie Thurman (Jackson 1970) with stuffed animal and Linda Towle with Alpha Omicron Pi dog paddle, 1967; MS266.000084 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle, age 20, blowing out candles on birthday cake in dorm room, 1967 September 24; MS266.000085 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Women seated on the floor in dorm room, 1967; MS266.000086 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Women seated on the floor in dorm room, 1967; MS266.000087 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Valentine's Day cards and chocolates on desk in dorm room, 1968 February; MS266.000088 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fred Cardin (Tufts 1968) portrait, MS266.000089 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sylvia Soffron blowing out candles on birthday cake in dorm room, 1968; MS266.000090 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fred Cardin and Linda Towle seated at table at Alpha Omicron Pi formal, 1968 April 27; MS266.000091 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Students on library roof at Senior Week event, Marcia Linda on right, 1968 June 5; MS266.000092 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Group of students at Senior Week event on library roof, 1968 June 5; MS266.000093 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Group of students at wine tasting, 1968 June 5; MS266.000094 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fred Cardin (Tufts 1968) and Linda Towle at Senior Prom, 1968 June 7; MS266.000095 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Malcolm McNeill, Vi Bekeris, and Linda Towle seated at outdoor table, 1968 June 8; MS266.000096 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fred Cardin (Tufts 1968) posed in front of building in New York City, Wall Street, 1968 December 1; MS266.000097 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Christmas card photograph of Fred Cardin and brother posed in car, 1968; MS266.000098 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Trees covered in snow, 1969; MS266.000099 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle's new Chevy, 1969 March 25; MS266.000100 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle posed with new Chevy, 1969 March 25; MS266.000101 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle's yearbook portrait, 1969; MS266.000102 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle in cap and gown, 1969 June 1; MS266.000103 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle in cap and gown, 1969 June 1; MS266.000104 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Charlie, Linda, and Marjorie Howard Towle at Commencement, 1969 June 1; MS266.000105 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle in cap and gown posed next to "Liberal Arts" sign, 1969 June 1; MS266.000106 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle in cap and gown posed next to "Liberal Arts" sign, 1969 June 1; MS266.000107 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Charlie, Linda, and Marjorie Howard Towle posed next to "Liberal Arts" sign, 1969 June 1; MS266.000108 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linda Towle with Fred Cardin (Tufts 1968), 1969 January 18; MS266.000109 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bride and bridesmaids posed at Vi Bekeris and Malcolm McNeill's wedding, 1969 August 16; MS266.000110 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Formal wedding portrait of Vi Bekeris and Malcolm McNeill, 1969 August 16; MS266.000111 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Formal portrait of bridal party at Vi Bekeris and Malcolm McNeill's wedding, 1969 August 16; MS266.000112 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Fred Cardin (center) in Harvard Business School classroom, 1969; MS266.000113 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Cars and buildings in snow, 1969 February; MS266.000114 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tufts campus after snowstorm, 1969; MS266.000115 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tufts campus after snowstorm, 1969; MS266.000116 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tufts campus after snowstorm, 1969; MS266.000117 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tufts campus after snowstorm, 1969; MS266.000118 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tufts campus after snowstorm, 1969; MS266.000119 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Tufts campus after snowstorm, 1969; MS266.000120 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal expenses, 1965 September -- 1966 May; MS266.000121 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sign out cards, December 1966 -- June 1968; MS266.000122 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tuition bills, 1965 August -- 1969 January; MS266.000123 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Invitations, 1965 October -- 1968 March; MS266.000124 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cards and notes from Jackson classmates, 1965 -- 1968; MS266.000125 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi material, 1966 -- 1968; MS266.000126 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi chapter member photographs, 1966 -- 1968; MS266.000127 (Box Shared 126)
  - Four Years, 2011 May 06; MS266.000128
  - Marjorie Howard at Tufts, 2019 June 13; MS266.000129